Alright, here's an example of how to land a fish on a jig rod.
I've got a fish on.
Not too big.
You can see a little bit of a bend in the rod.
But the most important thing to do when you're landing a fish on a jig rod is, always maintain a straight line.
You don't want any slack in the line because that's going to give that fish an opportunity to get off the hook.
So in, so you always want that slack, you always want that line nice and straight.
You want to keep your rod tip up a bit.
Let the fish, if the fish wants to fight, this one's not, not fighting real well, but if the fish wants to fight and take out line like this, let it go.
Let it take its line, let it tire himself out and be patient.
Above all, you have to be patient.
Now when you get that fish up towards the hole, what I like to do is just kneel down a little bit so I can help to guide it up if I need to.
Even reach my hand down into the hole if I need to.
And here we've got a nice little large mouth bass.
Nothing big, but that's, but those basic points still hold true for any, any size fish.
Be patient.
Don't allow any slack in the line, and bring it up.
When the fish wants to take line, let it take line and you'll land more fish.